Brandon O'Briant

Lakewood, WA 98498 obrianbl@protonmail.com • <u>www.linkedin.com/in/brandonobriant/</u> (253) 389 - 8507

Data Analyst

Multifaceted analytical professional with outstanding technical, research, and computational skills

Technically sophisticated analyst with recent academic background in predictive analytics, 2+ years of experience in SQL and Logical data modeling, and solid skills in programming and strategic planning. Broad knowledge of statistics, mathematics, computer systems, and programming languages. Ability to provide reports, analyze data, manage records and documents, and coordinate with a variety of teams and stakeholders. Extensive knowledge of Excel, Python, and R to value and compare valuations of companies. Experience in design thinking from inception to presentation in econometrics and business finance training projects. Commitment to highest quality and research accuracy and achievement of common goals. Excellent discipline, focus, and communication skills.

Core Competencies:

- Team Cooperation
- Research Methods
- Project Planning & Execution
- Data Science & Data Analysis Tools
- Project Report Writing
- Quantitative Analysis Models
- Relationship Management
- Problem Resolution & Troubleshooting

Professional Experience

Technical Training Projects

Northwestern University MSPA, 2017

- Exploratory Data Analysis of Abalone Dataset: Used programming language R as well as EDA methods (variation in variables, center/location of distributions, and outliers detection) to identify characteristic differences between abalone classes and analyze performance of methods from a previous study. Performed variance and linear regression analysis to construct and evaluate binary decision rules for practical harvesting level of abalones.
- Residential Real Estate Analysis: Analyzed variables and 506 census tract observations from the Boston Housing Study using linear regression within a cross-validation design to assess market value of residential real estate. Translated the results into a recommendation for the management. In another study variation, employed four different random forests and concluded that random forests method performed better than the other four for predicting market value. Used programming language Python.
- Client Banking History Project: Effectively managed project timeline, used four variables (default, balance, housing, and loan), and employed logistic regression and linear support vector machine within a cross-validation design. Wrote a report on problem, methods, results, and recommendations. Used programming language Python.

Pacific Lutheran University, 2016

• Fuzzy Set Theory: Application in Forecasting: Researched Fuzzy Logic/Set theory and formulated a detailed comparative analysis to 'crisp' logic.

Pierce College, Ft. Steilacoom, Lakewood, WA

Physics Lab Technician, 01/2014 - 06/2014

Assisted the physics department with setting up and calibrating course physic experiments equipment. Co-created quizzes, exams, and study materials for Geology 101. Commended for attention to detail and timeliness.

Pierce College, Ft. Steilacoom, Lakewood, WA

Library Assistant, 09/2012-05/2013

During my shift I was responsible for fielding technical issues and questions pertaining to computer hardware/software for the library patrons. Other duties included:

- Restocked shelves with the books in their proper place.
- Cleaned and maintained computers in the library.
- Assisted patrons with locating books/information or referred them to a librarian who specialized in their questions.
- Created a positive and approachable environment.

United States Marine Corps, San Diego, CA

Lance Corporal, 07/2003 – 05/2009, (2003-2004 Active)

- Implemented detailed plans to ensure the squad of eight and other subordinates would meet and exceed deadlines for supply, ceremonial, night watch, and weekly barrack/uniform inspections.
- Maintained professional etiquette during civilian and military installations related to supplies, warehousing, and transportation. Recorded visits and performed quarter deck watch.

Technical Proficiencies

Certifications: edX: Microsoft Professional Program Certificate in Data Science: Introduction

to Python for Data Science; Udemy: R Basics, The Numpy Stack in Python

Languages: Python, R, HTML

Databases: MySQL, NoSQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Visualization: Azure Studio, NetLogo, Tableau

Version Control: Git+GitHub

Productive Applications: Microsoft Office Suite, LaTex

Relevant Course Work: Practical Machine Learning, Regression and Multi Analysis, Database System

and Data Preparation, Database Management, Computational Science Modeling and Simulation, Mathematics of Risk, Probability/Statistical Theory, Business Finance, Linear Algebra (Theory/Applied), Data and Error Analysis

Education and Credentials

Master of Science in Predictive Analytics, GPA 3.75, Northwestern University, Evanston, IL, 2018

Bachelor of Science in Mathematics, GPA 3.09, Pacific Lutheran University, Parkland, WA, 2016

Associate of Arts in Mathematics, GPA 3.57, Pierce College Ft. Steilacoom, Lakewood, WA, 2014

Natural Science Outstanding Student for Mathematics, Pierce College Ft. Steilacoom, Lakewood, WA, 2013-2014